nationalnotary.org 2019-10-12

# Privacy Policy | NNA

(Last updated: July 2019)

The National Notary Association (NNA) is committed to protecting your privacy. This NNA Privacy Statement governs the data collection and usage within the NNA family of Web sites: NationalNotary.org, SigningAgent.com, NNAcnap.org and any other domain under the ownership or control of the NNA (the “NNA family of Web sites”). By visiting these Web sites, you consent to the practices set forth in this Privacy Statement. Please take a moment to review the sections below.

### Collection of Your Personal Information

The personally identifiable information we collect includes information you submit to us. Because submission of such information is completely voluntary, you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

The NNA may require you to enter personal information, including your name, email address, home address and telephone number when you contact us with an inquiry through our Web site. We will use such personal information for the sole purpose of contacting you with a response to your inquiry.

You also may register with the NNA by creating a “My NNA Profile.” To register, the NNA requires you to submit your name, email address, and to select a unique password. When creating your account, you must provide complete and accurate information on your own behalf using your own information, and you must keep your unique password secure. You alone are responsible for any activity that occurs on your account.

If you choose to place an order through NationalNotary.org, we require you to provide your name, shipping and billing address, email address, phone number and credit card information. This personal information is only used for order fulfillment, credit authorization, and to contact you regarding NNA business. Personal information for the role of credit card authorization may be shared with a third-party credit card processing center.

The NNA may collect information required by the states for Notary commissioning and auditing purposes, including but not limited to personal information data such as driver’s license or passport information. This information will be retained for the period designated by the commissioning state, even if you opt out or exercise your Right to be Forgotten in the European Union. Information collected for commissioning purposes may be shared with the commissioning state upon their request for the purposes of confirming commissioning information and/or auditing.

The NNA also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, referring website addresses and pages visited within NNA Web sites. This information is used by the NNA for the operation of our websites, to maintain quality of the services offered, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the NNA websites.

The NNA encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from the NationalNotary.org so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Although you may find links to many third party sites on the NNA family of Web sites, the NNA is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the NNA family of websites.

### Use and Sharing of Your Personal Information

The NNA collects and uses your personal information to operate its family of Web sites and deliver the content and services you have requested. Your personal information may be used to inform you of other products or services available from the NNA. The NNA may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

The NNA does not sell, rent or lease its member/customer lists to third parties. The NNA may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your personal information (email , name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. See also the section below regarding background screenings.

To the extent permitted by law, the NNA may disclose any information (personal and non-personal) collected over our Web sites, or concerning their use, to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, or other process that requires disclosure of information. We may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to collect debts, fight fraud or protect the rights or property of the NNA, our customers, our Web sites, or third parties, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it.

Moreover, in the event of a corporate change in control resulting from, for example, a sale to, or merger with, another entity, the NNA reserves the right to transfer your personal information to the new party in control.

### Collection, Use and Sharing of Personal Information for Background Screening

When you apply for NNA certification to be a Signing Agent or other NNA certification, the NNA will engage a third-party service provider to conduct a background check on you. As part of the background screening process, we require that you provide your name, shipping address, email address and phone number. The NNA will transmit this information, in encrypted form, to our service provider for processing.

Once our service provider has received your information, it will send you an email directing you to a secure Web site that will allow you to access the application for NNA certification. To complete your application, and to permit our service provider to conduct the required background screening, you will be asked to provide personal information, including your Social Security number, mother’s maiden name, date of birth, driver’s license number, as well as your email address and your home address. The personal information collected from applications will be used to obtain a consumer report to help us determine whether you meet the criteria for NNA certification, and thus, such information may be used for employment purposes in accordance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act. Providing this information, including your Social Security number, is voluntary and you may refuse. However, if you do not provide us with this information, we will not be able to process your application to obtain NNA certification.

The results of your background screening will be made available to the financial industry, title insurance companies, their affiliates and/or subcontractors, on SigningAgent.com.

For more information about the background screening process, please see overview of our Signing Agent Certification.

### Use of Cookies

The NNA uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. For each visitor to our website, our web server automatically recognizes and collects only your domain name, but not your e-mail address, unless you volunteer it.  A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. The NNA uses standard cookie technology, which you can disable through your web browser options, to store visitor's preferences, record session information, such as items that consumers add to their shopping cart, and record past activity at a site. 

We do not use cookie technology to harvest email addresses or other personal information. Additionally, when you view our website by linking from another web page we may store the name of that web page. All information collected through cookies is for internal use only and is used to compile aggregate information to analyze site, page, and service usage and consumer purchasing behavior. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, as a member of the NNA Community, a cookie helps recall your specific information on subsequent visits enabling you to access such sections from the same computer without the need to log-in multiple times. These cookies are used solely for session management and do not contain any personal information.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the NNA websites you visit.

Our goal is to provide you with the best possible experience on our website. For more information on cookies and how the NNA uses them, please visit www.nationalnotary.org/cookies.

### Access to Special Content and Services

Some areas and content on our website may require you to register with us or log in in order to access such areas and/or content.

### Control of Your Personal Information

As a Customer or NNA member, you may log in to the NNA Community and select My NNA to view and/or edit your personal information at any time. Please keep in mind that changing your address after an order has been placed will not change the shipping address for the order. To make a change to a shipping address after placing an order, you will need to contact customer service at 1-800-876-6827.

As a Signing Agent, you may log in to My NNA and select Update Your Profile to view and/or edit your personal information within your listing on SigningAgent.com. All personal information included within your SigningAgent.com listing is considered “public” and is viewable by registered companies searching the SigningAgent.com Directory. The NNA urges you to be careful only to enter information on your SigningAgent.com listing that you are comfortable sharing with registered SigningAgent.com companies.

In each case described above, you will be asked to make your requests while logged into a secure area, so that the NNA can associate your preferences with a particular account.

As part of your NNA membership, you may receive periodic emails informing you of technical service issues, product surveys, featured news articles and news about NNA products and services. These emails provide an option for you to unsubscribe to future mailings.

In the event that the Customer or NNA Member is denied access to this information for any reason, please contact our Customer Care department to resolve this access issue and/or to look up a user ID or reset a password to gain access.  Password resets can be performed online on a self-serve basis as well.

As a Customer or NNA member, if you have a concern that there has been a breach of your private information or our website, please contact customer service at 1-800-876-6827.  We will immediately launch an investigation and report back to you any results of this search.

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident and have shared personal information with us, California law may give you the right to request and obtain from us, once per calendar year, information about how we have shared your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. You may send such requests to us via postal mail at: National Notary Association, 9350 De Soto Ave., Chatsworth, CA 91311. If applicable, such information would include a list of the names and addresses of all third parties with whom personal information was shared during the prior calendar year for such third parties’ marketing purposes, as well as a list of the categories of personal information shared during such prior calendar year.

### Security of Your Personal Information

The NNA takes reasonable precautions to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. Nevertheless, NNA does not warrant or represent that its level of security meets or exceeds any particular standard. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever 100% secure or error-free.

### Do Not Track

NNA supports Do Not Track (DNT) Signals. DNT is a preference you can set in your internet browner to let websites you visit know that you do not want them collecting certain information about you. NNA allows third party tracking through its website. However, by implementing the DNT preference in your browser you will also prevent any third parties from tracking your information.

### Children’s Online Privacy

The NNA family of Web sites, and the content contained therein, is not directed at children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide personally identifiable information of any kind whatsoever. If a child does provide us with personally identifiable information, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us by sending an email to [webmaster@nationalnotary.org](mailto:webmaster@nationalnotary.org), calling us at 1-800-876-6827, or writing to:

NNA Privacy (Web)  
National Notary Association  
9350 De Soto Ave.  
Chatsworth, CA 91311

Upon notification, we will use comercially best efforts to delete from our records any information collected from children under the age of 13.

### Non-U.S. Users

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that the information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the NNA family of Web sites, you consent to this transfer. You also consent to the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with this Web site in the federal and state courts of, and in accordance with the laws of, the state of California.

### Changes to this Statement

The NNA will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how the NNA will use your personal information, the NNA will prominently post changes prior to implementing the change. The NNA reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to modify, alter or otherwise update this policy at any time and you agree to be bound by such modifications, alterations or updates. Your continued use of our websites constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Statement and any updates. Therefore, we encourage you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how the NNA is collecting, using and protecting your information.

### Contact Information

The NNA welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. Please contact us with any comments, questions or concerns by telephone, email or postal mail.

NNA Privacy (Web)  
National Notary Association  
9350 De Soto Ave.  
Chatsworth, CA 91311  
1-800-876-6827
